-= CHD字幕组 原创翻译 =-
字幕仅供翻译学习交流 谢绝用于任何商业用途
翻译：Victor Sambug 蟋蟀
校订：dahongying
快看！在那儿！
有敌机！
在那儿！看啊！
报警！快准备！
长崎将被袭击了！
快找掩体！
你们要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
救救我！
Help me!
在这儿！
Over here!
停下！别开枪！别开枪！
你！
You!
快走！
Go!
那是B29轰炸机，老弟
That was a b-29, bub.
这玩意儿来了跑也没用
There's no outrunning what's coming.
矢志田！
矢志田，你在干什么？！过来！
矢志田，过来啊！
想活命就下来躲着
You're better off down here.
- 矢志田！  - 是，我马上就来！
我要是你就抓紧时间
I'd hurry if I were you.
快跑！
Run. Now!
趴下！
Stay down!
不，等等！再等等！
No, wait! No, no. Wait.
不 外面不安全
No. It's not safe.
醒醒，醒醒，醒醒
Wake up, wake up, wake up.
醒醒
Wake up.
梦到什么了？
Where were you?
长崎
Nagasaki.
又是那事？
That far back?
你来啦
You're here.
是啊
Of course.
能留下来吗？
Can you stay?
你知道不行的
You know I can't.
珍，我很抱歉
Jean, I'm so sorry.
我明白
I know.
我再也不会伤害你或者其他人了
I'll never hurt you or anyone ever again.
我发誓
I made a vow.
郑重起誓吗？
A solemn vow?
你在嘲笑我
You're making fun of me.
太晚了
It's too late.
不！不，珍！
No! No, Jean!
不，不，不！求你了！
No, no, no! Please!
你躲不了的
You can't hide.
不，不，不！不要
No, no, no! Please!
你躲不了的！
You can't hide!
不，珍！不要！
No, Jean! No!
不
No.
（法洛五金店）
账都先赊着 谢谢啦，亲爱的
Whack all of that on store credit. Thanks, honey.
- 买箭了吗？   - 买了
- Got the arrows? - Yeah.
别忘了买箭
Remember the arrows?
好了，知道了，埃迪，买到了！
Yeah, yeah, Eddie, we got them!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
兄弟，你差点打飞他的脚！
Man, you almost blew his foot off!
你不是猎人吧？
You're not a hunter, are you?
不再是了
Not anymore.
出了什么事？
What the hell?
别逼我这么做
Don't make me do this.
它绝对有近12英尺高
It must have been damn near 12 feet tall.
除了树枝被踩断的声音我们啥也没听见
We didn't hear nothing except twigs.
它就这样猛地冲了出来
Then it just came upon us.
它杀了赖利，内脏扯了一地
It got Riley, just gutted him.
还杀了埃迪
It got Eddie.
帐篷被撕得粉碎
Ripped through the tent,
雪地车像玩具一样被撞翻了
knocked over the snowcat like it was a toy.
你就是被灰熊袭击的那个人？
You the one was attacked by the grizzly?
我是唯一幸存下来的
I'm the one that survived.
我想请这位先生喝酒
I'd like to buy this man a drink.
你叫什么名字，先生？
What's your name, mister?
罗根
It's Logan.
这箭头抹了毒药
And that's a poison broadhead,
据我所知，这是非法的
which, last I heard, was illegal.
继续，问我是在哪儿找到的
Go ahead, ask me where I found it.
快点问我
Ask me.
你在哪儿找到的？
Where did you find it?
嗯，问得好
Well, funny you should ask.
是从一头灰熊身上拔出来来的
I pulled it out of the back of a grizzly.
不管是谁射的，都没有能力和胆量
Whoever shot it, didn't have the wind or the balls
正确追踪猎物…
to track the animal properly...
并且快速结束它的痛苦
And put it out of its misery.
相反你们却下毒…
Instead of dropping a lethal dose of the poison...
毒药渗进熊的体内
It bled into the bear,
逼得它发疯
made him crazy,
丢了五条人命
killed five people.
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
那是因为我从来不在箭上抹毒
Because I don't dip my arrows in anything.
既然这样，那也就没什么好怕的了
In that case, you got nothing to worry about.
见你的鬼
Damn.
这很疼啊
That hurt.
对不起了，珍
Sorry, Jean.
不用为他们操心
I wouldn't bother with them.
他们大多也是死路一条，不用你出手
Most of them will die soon anyway, without your help.
他们中的三个，一周内都会被同一辆车撞死
Three of them, a week from now in the same truck.
这把剑有几百年的历史了…
This sword is hundreds of years old...
被第一位使用它的武士命名为“谈山”
And was named Danzan by the first samurai who used it.
谈山在日文里的意思就是“分离器”
Danzan means "separator" in Japanese.
把脑袋和四肢从躯体上分离开的完美武器
The ideal weapon for separating head and limb from body.
就像这样
Like so.
我在后门等你
I'm parked in back.
上车
Get in.
对不起，车是租的
Sorry, it's a rental.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我？我叫雪绪
Me? I'm Yukio.
然后呢？
And?
我已经找了你一年多了
I've been trying to find you for over a year.
为什么？
Why?
为了给你这个
To give you that.
雇我的人想让你收下它
My employer wanted you to have it.
谁是你的雇主？
Who's your employer?
矢志田主人
Master Yashida.
他说这柄剑属于你
He said it belongs to you,
他要还债
and that he's paying all debts.
矢志田主人快死了
Master Yashida is dying.
他想向你道谢
He wants to say thank you
为了你多年前的救命之恩
for saving his life all those years ago.
他知道你是个…
He knows that you are a...
大忙人
Busy man.
但他很想亲自和你道别
But he very much wants to say his goodbye in person.
好吧，他在哪儿？
All right, where is he?
东京
Tokyo.
等等… 我可不去日本
Wait... I'm not going to Japan.
拒绝他的请求是很无礼的
It would be dishonorable for you to refuse his request.
那么，代我向矢志田先生道歉
Well, apologize to Mr. Yashida,
我不会去东京的
I'm not going to Tokyo.
好吗？我还有很多事
All right? I've got things to do.
不必道歉
Do not apologize.
能见到金刚狼本尊已经很荣幸了
It's been an honor just to meet the Wolverine.
我已经不是从前的我了，明白吗？
That's not who I am anymore, you understand?
有意思
Interesting.
你干吗还跑到酒吧里去了
Why did you go into that bar,
不是为了寻求正义吗？
if not to seek justice?
- 我不知道   - 你不知道
- I don't know. - You don't know.
- 是的！ - 我觉得你知道
- No! - I think you know.
- 停车   - 你是个战士
- Pull over. - You are a soldier.
不，我不是 停车
No, I'm not. Pull over.
你就是个战士
You are a soldier.
赶紧停车！
Pull over, now!
快点
Now.
你是个战士
You are a soldier,
你所寻求的和其他战士是一样的
and you seek what all soldiers do.
什么呢？
And what's that?
光荣战死
An honorable death.
结束痛苦
An end to your pain.
谁说我很痛苦？
Who says I'm in pain?
一个人一辈子都在做同一个噩梦就是痛苦
A man who has nightmares every night of his life is in pain.
就一天
One day.
我和矢志田先生道别后就马上回来
I say goodbye to Mr. Yashida and I come right back.
没问题
okay.
要飞15个小时 还得取决于风向
Fifteen hours. Depending on the wind.
15个小时？
Fifteen hours?
你不喜欢坐飞机？
You don't like to fly?
很喜欢
I love it.
Kuzuri.
Kuzuri 是什么意思？
Kuzuri. What does that mean?
怪兽
Monster.
不疼吗？
No pain?
- 你没有…  - 哦，是的，很疼
- You have no... - Oh, yeah. Pain.
非常疼
Plenty of pain.
你几岁了？
How old are you?
反正活得够久了
It's been a long time.
经历了很多战争
Many wars.
明白吗？
Understand?
太多的战争了
Too many fuckin' wars.
快到了
We are almost there.
你能预知未来？
So, you can see the future?
我会看地图
I can read a map.
你说你知道酒吧里那些混蛋的下场
You said you knew the future of those assholes in the bar.
我知道他们会死
I know they are going to die.
我们都会死
We are all going to die.
你说他们会在一周内被同一辆车撞死
You said they would die in the same truck, in a week.
如果你说中了，那可是个了不起的天赋
If you're right, that's quite a talent.
不是每个人都有钢爪的
We don't all have claws.
那么，我会死于空难吗？
So, do I die on this plane?
不会
No.
不是这架飞机
Not on this plane.
别被繁华的表象所迷惑
Don't let the lights fool you.
其实背后充满黑暗
These are dark days in Japan.
有人相信矢志田主人生病后
Some believe when master Yashida got sick,
有个黑影一直伴其左右
a shadow fell upon us.
你觉得他是神吗？
Do you think he's a God?
不 是个人
No. A man.
但很伟大
But a great one.
战后，他参与了国家重建
After the war, he helped rebuild the nation.
家族产业也成了日本第一
And the family business became Japan's largest.
他们给你纪念卡片了吗？
Did they give you a little card to memorize?
矢志田主人救了我的命
I owe master Yashida my life.
别得寸进尺
Don't be a dick.
戒备森严啊
A lot of guns.
这里发生了多起袭击事件
There have been attacks.
绑架未遂
Attempted kidnappings.
暗杀未遂
Attempted assassinations.
谁干的？
By who?
一个日本社团，黑帮
The Japanese mob, the Yakuza.
趁着政府萎靡不振他们日益强大
They've grown strong as the government has grown weak.
- 他身上有枪  - 他没问题
- 雪绪小姐，他带有枪  - 我说过了他没问题
我做过髋关节置换手术
Hip replacement.
请穿鞋
鞋太小了
Uh, too small.
太小了
Too small.
这边请
this way.
他是谁？
Who's that?
他叫信玄，矢志田主人的儿子
Shingen, master Yashida's son.
武艺不错
He's good.
一般吧
He's all right.
好久不见
穿靴子的坏蛋出了什么事？
So, what happened to the badass in boots?
矢志田主人非常传统
Master Yashida is traditional.
既着眼于过去又着眼于未来
One eye on the past and the other on the future.
必须死…
对于抚养你是最合适的人选…
- 我不想做那种事情，爷爷…  - 只有你能做到…
那是真理子，她的孙女
That's Mariko, his granddaughter.
真理子
怎么了？发生什么事了？
最近也都没回我我邮件
现在不能告诉你
为什么？说清楚些啊
那个脏兮兮的人是谁？
他就是矢志田大人说要我找的人
给他收拾干净了再让他见爷爷
静和佐纪会为你沐浴
Shizu and saki are going to disinfect you.
刮脸
Give you a shave.
想都别想
Like hell they are.
快进浴盆
Get in the tub.
给我进去
当真？
Really?
快坐好！快坐好！快坐好！
好了
All right.
- 别乱动啊！  - 怎么样？很舒服吧
就这么别动！
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
行了，行了，行了
All right, all right, all right.
我自己能行
I can do that bit.
干嘛？
What?
干什么？
你挺帅的
You look nice.
我觉着被侵犯了似的
I feel violated.
为矢志田主人多准备两管抑制剂
Prepare two more suppressors for master Yashida.
检查他的血压
And check his blood pressure.
矢志田大人
你找的人已到了
Kuzuri.
别来无恙啊
You look the same.
不过，这也不稀奇
But, then, that is no surprise.
格林医生
Dr. green.
请回避一下
Leave us, please.
最多五分钟
Five minutes, no more.
我的肿瘤医师
My oncologist.
干得漂亮
Well done.
哦，不必了
Oh, forget the etiquette.
我受够了这些预防措施
I'm past such precautions.
多年以来
For many years
我一直想感谢你的救命之恩
I have wanted to thank you for saving my life.
你对我很好
You were kind to me.
对别人也很好
And you were kind to many people.
即便在井里我也能感觉到
I saw that even from that well.
那幅画上是我出生的小镇
The painting is from the village of my birth.
画的是智勇双全的黑色联盟
It depicts the bravery and skill of the black clan.
忍者武士
Ninja warriors.
他们侍奉我的家族七百年了
They served my family for seven centuries.
我不仅仅是要感谢你，罗根
I didn't send for you only to thank you, Logan.
我想报答你
I wanted to repay you.
给予你别人所给予不了的
To offer you something no one else can.
一份和我的生命同样珍贵的礼物
A gift to equal the life you gave to me.
我不需要任何东西
I don't need anything.
它可不是物品
Not a thing.
永生是个诅咒
Eternity can be a curse.
对你来说绝非易事，活得没有时限
It hasn't been easy for you, living without time.
忍受失去的痛苦
The losses you have had to suffer.
会让人失去活着的动力
A man can run out of things to live for.
丧失他的目标
Lose his purpose.
成为一名浪人
Become a ronin.
没有主人的武士
A samurai without a master.
我可以结束你的永生
I can end your eternity.
让你变成凡人
Make you mortal.
他们对我的所作所为
What they did to me, what I am,
是无法消除的
can't be undone.
矢志田产业无所不能
Yashida industries can do anything.
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe
你的自愈能力可以被转移
that your ability to heal can be passed.
转移？
Passed?
转移到另一个人身上
From you to another.
你挣扎的够久了，罗根
You have struggled long enough, Logan.
我不明白
I'm confused.
我是来向一位故人道别的
I came here to say goodbye to a man I once knew.
我还是我
I am the same man.
以前我没有准备好去死
I was not ready to die then.
现在也没有准备好
I am not ready to die now.
但你不是…
But you are...
对吗？
Aren't you?
- 你是要杀了我吗？   - 不
- Are you offering to kill me? - No.
不是马上
Not right away.
你能过上长寿平凡的日子
You can live a long and ordinary life.
恋爱，成家…
Fall in love, have a family...
变老
Grow old.
然后在某一天
And one day,
平凡离世
die an ordinary death.
这些都能做到
It can be done.
好吧，听我说
Yeah, look,
很高兴再次见到你
nice to see you again.
我很抱歉你病了
Sorry you got sick.
求你了，罗根君 我需要你的帮助
Please, Logan-San. I need you again.
我担心我的家族
I fear for my family.
担心我所创造的一切
I fear for everything I have built.
- 够了 你该走了   - 求你了，罗根君
- Enough. You should leave. - Please, Logan-San.
她会被杀死的
They're going to kill her.
谁？
Who?
真理子，我的孙女
Mariko, my granddaughter.
她是我的宝贝
She is my treasure.
她必须得到保护
She must be protected.
你不会想要我的能力的
You don't want what I've got.
Kuzuri.
Kuzuri!
信玄老爷，令尊有请
也是时候了
父亲！父亲，父亲…
在他和爷爷面谈之前
我有话要和父亲说
让开，让我进去
他一会儿会和你谈的，小姐
我现在就要见您！父亲！
现在不是时候，真理子！
- 求你了，父亲！  - 肃静！
等等，父亲 求你了，听我说
- 求你了，听我说，爸爸  - 别再烦我！
- 求你了，听我说  - 我现在没有时间
- 就因为爷爷选择了我…  - 我说过了，闭嘴！
你就是不在乎，所以爷爷才会…
真理子大小姐！
小心，小心 这里滑的很
Careful, careful. It's slippery out here.
放开我
Let go.
闹够了吗？
You about done?
放开我
Let go of me.
他就是想道个别，是吧？
He just wanted to say goodbye, huh?
你们俩一起长大的
You two grew up together.
是的
Yes.
但你不是她的亲妹妹
But you're not her sister.
是的
No.
矢志田主人在一次南方旅行中找到了我
Master Yashida found me on a trip to the South.
他带着真理子看在建的厂房
He brought Mariko to see a factory he was building.
当时我在垃圾堆里找吃的
I was digging through the garbage for something to eat.
所以他们就带你一起回家了？
So they just took you home with them?
交朋友对于真理子来说一向很难
It was always difficult for Mariko to make friends.
我去看看明早的飞机是否备妥
I'll see to it the plane is ready in the morning.
你就睡这儿
Sleep here.
别摆那么一张失望的脸啊，信玄
我还没死呢
需要我的话，我就在办公室
I'll be in my office if you need me.
说这些话不容易
但是，你我之间从来就没有过轻松的交流，不是吗？
我尽力吧，父亲
你已经尽力了
你一直以来就是我的第一继承人
You have always been my assumed successor.
所以过去的今年，为了培养你，
So the past few years, as a test,
我给予你更多的权力
I allowed you more control.
荣幸之至
It has been an honor.
但现在我意识到这是个错误
And I now realize that was a mistake.
你已经把公司带向了毁灭的边缘
You have brought this company close to ruin.
这些话我想应该重新…
我死后
When I die,
会有别人接替我的主席一职
someone else will take my place as chairman.
父亲，如果我让您失望了，我很抱歉…
Father, I'm sorry if I have disappointed you...
我们就别再互相指责了
Let's not insult one another.
你不是那个领导矢志田的人
You are not the man to lead Yashida.
可您也不能一个外人来接管家族事业啊
You cannot bring in someone from the outside.
这个，你倒是说对了
In that, you are correct.
我绝不会让它发生的
永生就是个诅咒…
Eternity can be a curse...
Kuzuri.
你没有痛觉吗，Kuzuri？
You have no pain, Kuzuri?
你几岁了？
How old are you?
这个提议有点意思
Interesting offer.
为什么要拒绝呢？
What are you doing turning the old man down?
我以为你想要和我在一起
I thought you wanted to be with me.
过来
Come here.
他死了
He's dead.
我没能预见到
I didn't foresee it.
作为矢志田一郎最大的支持者和后盾，你对主人家有什么看法？
这个不好说
真理子旁边的是谁？
Who's that? With Mariko.
他叫茂吕升
His name is Noburo Mori.
司法部长，前途无量
Minister of justice, a rising star.
他是真理子的未婚夫
He's Mariko's fiance.
你得鞠躬
You need to bow.
鞠躬
Bow.
信玄大人，这位是罗根先生
Lord Shingen, this is Mr. Logan.
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
令尊是个好人
Your father was a good man.
他时常这样说起你
He would often say the same about you.
但是，他也总是痴迷于你这类人
But then, he was always fascinated with your kind.
告诉我，你凭什么认为
Tell me, why do you think
他会派小雪绪来请你呢？
he sent our little Yukio to fetch you?
为了道别
To say goodbye.
那现在你已经道过了
And now you have.
该是你滚回老家的时候了
Time for you to go back to your cave.
还想让我见谁？
Anyone else you want me to meet?
我向您保证…
矢志田主人…
随时保持警惕…
用我的生命…
来保护真理子
这套铠甲属于Shiruba武士的…
That armor belonged to shiruba-samurai...
也就是银武士
The silver samurai.
他会生生世世守护在老人身边
It will stand watch over the old man forever.
罗根？
Logan?
有点不对劲儿
Something's not right.
放开我
Let go.
可以退到后面来吗？
请退回来！
退回来！
退后！
罗根！
Logan!
放开我！
罗根！
Logan!
你在拍什么呢！
老实点儿！
是那个外国佬！把他干掉！
Kuzuri.
走吧 快点，快走！
Let's go. Come on, let's go!
- 雪绪！   - 真理子！
- Yukio!        - Mariko!
你想去哪儿！
真理子！
Mariko!
那边儿！
快点 快走，快走
Come on. Let's go, let's go.
往这儿走！
Here, here! Here!
快走！
Move!
快进来！快！
In here! Move!
别想逃！死老外！
你跑不了啦！
继续走，不要停
Keep moving, keep moving.
走！
Move!
你在流血 需要包扎
You're bleeding. You need help.
先走吧
Just keep moving.
感谢你的帮助
Thank you for what you did back there.
- 那些人是黑帮的   - 我没事了
- Those were Yakuza. - I'm fine.
他们为什么跟踪你？
Why are they after you?
没事了 我一个人能离开这儿
I'm fine. I can make my way from here.
你也该走了
You should go.
去找个医生治伤
Get yourself a doctor.
（上野车站）
真舒服
That's nice.
这就是子弹头列车，对吗？
This is one of those bullet trains, right?
我说过了不需要你的帮助
I told you I don't need your help.
他们能跑多快，300英里时速？
So what do they do, like, 300 Miles an hour?
走这边，请上车吧
这次无耻的攻击事件…
是由黑帮暴徒一手策划的
针对我有效摧毁有组织犯罪行为的暴力回应
他们从北门跑了
她当时和那个陌生人在一起…
你那个外国朋友，是哪儿来的？
Your gaijin friend, where is he?
据我所见，他一直在保护您的女儿啊
Last I saw, he was protecting your daughter.
你只是个玩具娃娃
You are a toy doll.
一个孩子的玩伴，长大后就抛弃你
A companion for a child who has outgrown you.
记住这点
Keep that in mind.
哈优，没事吧？
那么，我们这是要去哪儿，真理子？
So, where are we headed, Mariko?
我们要去哪儿？
Where are we going?
我坐到终点站
I'm going to the end of the line.
我的家族在南方有个老宅子
My family has a home in the South.
愚蠢
That's stupid.
恕我冒犯
No offense,
但是他们肯定知道去那里找你的
but they're gonna know to look for you there.
总比这儿强
Not this place.
- 你想一个人去   - 是的
- You want to be left alone. - Yes.
- 我理解   - 是吗？
- I understand. - Do you?
是的 相信我
Oh, yeah. Trust me.
问题是，如果我不跟着你…
Problem is, if I do that...
恐怕你活不过今晚
I don't think you're gonna live to see the end of the day.
你不能假装什么事都没发生过
You can't pretend shit isn't happening when it is,
公主阁下
princess.
除非你想死
Unless you want to die.
否则，你就得加倍小心
In that case, you're playing this perfectly.
这是怎么了？
what the hell?
发生了什么事？
What the hell is happening?
是那个老外！
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
我们得离开这儿 快走
We get off here. Let's go.
听我说，好吗？
Just listen to me, will you?
我们得去找个安全的地方
We need to find someplace safe.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你怎么知道他们是黑帮的？
How do you know they were Yakuza?
他们和那些僧侣是一伙儿的
They were the same guys from the temple.
你怎么知道他们跟踪我？
How do you know they were after me?
我们得先找个安全的地方
Look, we need to find someplace safe.
我们不能暴露
We need to get off the streets.
- 我不明白   - 闭嘴！听着
- I don't understand. - Shut up! Listen.
你熟悉这里吗？市中心在哪儿？
Do you know this place? Where's downtown?
直走
Straight ahead.
闹市区在哪儿？
So, where's the nice part of town?
往前再走八个街区
Another eight blocks that way.
很好 我们就躲在这儿
Good. We're staying here.
走吧
Let's go.
这是情侣主题客栈
This is a love hotel.
什么客栈？
A what?
情侣主题客栈
A love hotel.
专供情侣住的，明白吗？
For couples, understand?
好吧
Right.
要两间房
uh, two rooms.
要同一楼层，相邻的两间房
Adjoining rooms, on the same floor.
两隔壁的 紧挨着的
Right next to each other. Very close.
要同一层的 同一层
Same floor. Same floor.
我们需要两间房间
有没有挨着的两间吗？
现在客人很多啊
现在空着的房间啊…
地牢特色房
护士特色房
火星探险房
她说什么来着？
What did she say?
她说没有紧挨着的房间了
She has no rooms available next to each other.
她在问我们是不是更喜欢
She's asking if we prefer
“地牢房”，“护士房”…
"the dungeon", "the nurse's office..."
或者“火星探险房”
Or the "mission to Mars."
这间不错
This'll do.
发射！我们要发射啦！
Liftoff! We have a liftoff!
老实说，挺温馨的
Kind of homey, actually.
打算怎么睡？
Where do you plan on sleeping?
不知道
I don't.
你流了很多血
That's a lot of blood.
我想英雄已经救美了
I thought you were done being the hero.
但是那些家伙… 会杀了她的
But these guys were... Trying to kill her.
别管了
Just let it go.
死其实不难
It's not hard to die.
跟我来吧
Come to me.
罗根…
Logan...
小心地滑
You're slipping.
站住，混蛋！别跑！
你是什么东西！
干掉他！快点！
罗根…
Logan...
快杀了他！
有什么临终遗言吗，外国佬？
Wanna say something before you die, gaijin?
怎么回事？谁啊？
不行！
- 让我来  - 不行 我不放心，不行
他醒过来了
这是老板娘美惠子
This is Mieko from the hotel
和他的孙子，仁志
and her grandson, Hitoshi.
他是医生吗？
Is he a doctor?
某种意义上说，是的
In a manner of speaking, yes.
他是名兽医…
He's a veterinarian...
学徒
Student.
专治大型动物
Large animal.
谢谢
Thanks.
你把他割伤了一两次
You may have cut him once or twice
在他为你缝合的时候
while he was stitching you.
好吧，不用谢，没关系
Okay, okay, okay.
我来收拾就行了
你们去休息一会儿吧
谢谢你
thank you.
我从来都不需要这些的
I never needed this before.
什么？治疗吗？
What? Help?
那个医生，治疗你爷爷的
That doctor, the one who helped your grandfather,
一头金发的
the blonde.
她是谁？
Who is she?
她是去年爷爷在美国接受治疗时认识的
He met her last year when he was in America for treatment.
你爷爷说我的自愈能力能被移除
Your grandfather told me my healing could be taken from me,
并转移
passed on.
我不如以前恢复的快了
I'm not getting better, not like before.
肯定是她捣的鬼
She did this to me.
美女！
Blondie!
那个金发美女，你等一下啊
美女！
Blondie!
等下，等下，等下 好正点啊
多少钱？多少钱，懂吗？多少钱过夜？
How much? How much, yeah? How much?
他没事儿吧？
你让我等了两小时
You kept me waiting two hours.
你太无礼了
You have no respect.
你没找着他们吧？
So you haven't found them?
别耍我，贱人 我会杀了你的
Don't play with me, bitch. I could kill you.
如果你杀了我
If you could make me feel something,
原田，那可就太高尚了
Harada, that would be sublime.
我会撕烂你的嘴
I can slit your pretty mouth open,
再敢说我是笨蛋的话…
before you open it to say one more stupid...
我只要求你做一件事，小家伙
I asked you to do one thing, little man.
把那个变异人带来
Bring me the mutant.
我不是你的手下 我受雇于…
I don't work for you. I work for the house of...
你为矢志田家族服务，这我知道
You work for Yashida, I get it.
但你并没有完成他的遗愿
Yet you cannot fulfill his dying wish.
天哪，知道你辜负了他多少心血吗
My God, if you had any idea how much you have failed him.
罗根在哪儿？我和他没完
Where is Logan? Lam not done with him.
那个变异人很强大
The mutant has powers.
现在只是个凡人罢了
He's just a man now.
他现在很虚弱
His flesh is weak now.
我的杰作
I did that.
我抑制了他的能力，他可以被打败
I suppressed his power so he could be taken.
知道了吧，现在对我客气点儿
You see, it's me you should respect.
赶在黑帮之前找到他们
Just find them, before the Yakuza.
我们在这里下车
We get off here.
我们在哪儿？
Where are we?
长崎外的某个地方
Just outside Nagasaki.
往这儿走
This way.
这不是出现在葬礼上的家伙嘛，那个弓箭手
This is the guy from the funeral, the archer.
他是你的前男友
He was your boyfriend.
他叫原田
That's Harada.
我们是那年夏天的小镇冠军
We were village champions that summer.
他是箭术冠军，而我是刀术冠军
He with the bow and me with the knives.
原田和我本打算结婚
Harada and I were planning to get married.
是谁阻止了你们？
What stopped you?
我爷爷
Grandfather.
他说至少要等到我们15岁之后
He said we had to wait until we were at least 15.
这是山货，这是海货
From the Mountain, from the sea.
- 我开吃了！  - 我开吃了！
筷子插在饭上是很不吉利的
Chopsticks upright are a bad omen.
就像葬礼上焚香一样
It resembles incense at a funeral.
世间万事都是有寓意的
Nothing is without meaning.
那么，那天晚上
So, the other night at the house,
你冲入雨幕…
when you ran out in the rain...
是什么寓意呢？
What did that mean?
我爷爷快死了
My grandfather was dying.
你知道他快死了
You knew he was gonna die.
他卧病在床多年
He'd been sick for a long time.
我怕的不是他的死
It wasn't his death I feared.
那你怕的是什么？
So, what, then?
那天晚上他和你说了些什么？
What did he tell you that night?
真理子，为什么你的父亲会打你？
Mariko, why did your father hit you?
我在试图警告他
I was trying to warn him.
警告什么？
About what?
你爷爷和你说了些什么？
What did your grandfather tell you?
他跟我说…
He told me that...
三天之内，宣读遗嘱的时候…
In three days, when they read his will...
我会成为全日本最有权势的人
I will become the most powerful person in Japan.
他把一切都给了我
He gave it all to me.
矢志田企业？
The company?
可我不想要
I didn't want it.
他早就料到
He knew that.
我就是不明白他为什么要给我
I don't understand why he gave it to me.
这一切都是我父亲日思夜想的
It was all my father dreamed of.
我想，这就是关键吧
Well, that's why.
你的未婚夫呢？毛驴
What about this fiance of yours? Nostromo.
茂吕
Noburo.
他知道这事吗？
Does he know about this?
不知道
No.
你为什么要嫁给他？
Why are you marrying him?
他就是个混球啊
He seems like kind of an asshole.
这是我父亲去年安排的
My father arranged it last year.
什么？
What?
我们的婚姻能在政坛上助他一臂之力
It gives him a better access to the political theater.
违背我父亲的意愿就是让他蒙羞
To disobey my father would be to dishonor him.
我不指望你能理解
I don't expect you to understand.
毕竟你不是日本人
You're not Japanese.
我们的国土又长又窄
就连火车都只能跑两个方向
我向您保证，信玄阁下…
我的人正在尽全力…
你们都是一群废物
你已经浪费了我太多的时间
我还要料理家父的后事
赶紧滚去找她！
告诉我你从内部带来的好消息吧
Tell me you have more promising news from your contacts.
遗嘱三天之内就要公布了
They open the will in three days.
我们快没时间了
We are running out of time.
快了
Soon,
我希望是
I hope.
我派了人去南方
I'm sending men to the South.
就是我们发现尸体的地方
That's where we found the bodies.
如果黑帮混入了葬礼队伍…
那他们肯定安插了内线
他们绝对找不到我的
你现在不安全
我来找你
他们会跟踪你的
拜托了
再等几天吧
求你了 我没事
罗根在这
真理子，他受伤了
真理子小姐
有人来了
真理子？
Mariko?
不说了
真理子？
Mariko?
- 真理子小姐  - 奶奶
真理子小姐，有一树倒在了路边
那个男人能帮上忙
- 茶好了  - 辛苦您了
茶有点儿热，您小心点儿
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
我累了
Tired.
你需要点什么吗？
Do you need something?
不
No.
- 你好啊  - 你好
- 我来个苹果？  - 苹果啊
这个能帮到你
This will help.
是时候了
It's time.
什么？
What?
求你了 收下吧
Please. Take it.
谢谢
Thank you.
不
No.
要握双手
Two hands.
日本的剑要双手握紧
Japanese sword require two hands.
- 像这样？  - 没错
- Like that? - That's it.
真是漂亮，矢志田
It's beautiful, Yashida.
但是我不能收下
But I can't take it.
求你
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
妥善保管
Keep it safe.
给我妥善保管
Keep it safe for me.
终有一天，我会来取
Someday, I'll come get it.
是时候了
It's time.
事发之时，我在现场
I was here when it happened.
我就是这样认识你的爷爷
It's how I met your grandfather.
我们躲在这里
We hid in there.
我听过你们的故事
I heard the stories.
我的爷爷会说…
My grandfather would say...
这里发生的事见证着
What happened here was proof
世界和平的出现
that everything in the world finds peace.
到最后
Eventually.
人类终能踏上复兴之路
That man can recover from anything.
或许你也一样
Maybe you, too.
你睡得不怎么好
You don't sleep very well.
夜里传来你的呼叫
You call out in the night.
谁是珍？
Who's Jean?
我们该回去了
We should go back.
大雨将至
There's rain coming.
我来烧茶
I'll make tea.
给你
For you.
这样不对
This isn't right.
你要系得像个真正的武士
You need this tied like a proper samurai.
你的爷爷称我为浪人
Your grandfather called me a ronin.
意思是没有主人的武士
A samurai without a master.
他说我命中注定长生不老…
He said I was destined to live forever...
没有意义地活下去
With no reason to live.
他说得对吗？
Was he right?
对
Yes.
现在还是？
Still?
你在干什么？
what are you doing?
不会有好的结果
This isn't going to end well.
你爱上的人都要死去
Everyone you love dies.
Kuzuri.
你知道什么意思吗？
Do you know what that means?
一种动物
An animal.
拥有长爪利牙的凶猛野兽
A fierce creature with long claws and sharp teeth.
它无所畏惧
It fears nothing.
我还是个女孩的时候
When I was a girl,
我做过恶梦
I had nightmares.
我醒来，然后奔向父母
I'd wake up and run to my parents.
我的父亲会发怒
My father would get angry.
别害怕，回到床上去
“回到梦中 面对你的恐惧”
"Go back to sleep. Face your fears."
我的爷爷则不同
My grandfather was different.
他告诉我关于Kuzuri的故事
He told me stories about Kuzuri,
他的朋友
his friend.
就是他在井底认识的那个人
Who he met at the bottom of a well.
他说Kuzuri是天神下凡
He said the Kuzuri was magical
守护他的生命
and saved his life.
他又说Kuzuri会守护我
He said Kuzuri would protect me, too,
在我入睡以后
as I slept in my bed.
谁是珍？
Who's Jean?
她喜欢你吗？
Is she like you?
她发生什么事了？
What happened to her?
她死了
She died.
我杀了她
I killed her.
还有Kuzuri
Along with the Kuzuri.
罗根
Logan.
真理子？
Mariko?
罗根！
Logan!
真理子？
Mariko?
真理子！
Mariko!
不要！罗根！
No! Logan!
不要！
No!
罗根！
Logan!
不要！
No!
真理子！
Mariko!
罗根！
Logan!
不要！
No!
罗根！
Logan!
真理子！真理子！
Mariko! Mariko!
罗根！
Logan!
他们把她带到什么地方？
Where are they taking her?
说话啊，废物？
Where, you piece of shit?
我不会说的，外国佬
I no talk, gaijin.
我不会说的
I never talk.
雇佣你的是谁？
Who hired you?
带我去找森信郎
Take me to Noburo.
罗根… 带我去找他
Logan... Take me to him.
我必须要告诉你一件事
I need to tell you something.
开车 快
Do it. Now.
你留在车里
You wait in the car.
- 罗根  - 什么？
- Logan. - What?
我预见到你的死
I saw you die.
什么？
What?
我预见到你的死
I saw you die.
什么时候？就刚才？
When? Just now?
不久前
Awhile ago.
但是我又看不到完整的画面
But it's not like I get a complete picture.
更像是管中窥豹
More like looking through a keyhole.
但是我的预感没有错过
But I'm always right.
我只能看到一个人一生的一小部分…
All I can see is one part of a person's life...
和他们的死亡
Their death.
如今，我看到你的
And I saw yours.
那么，你看到什么？
So, what did you see?
我看到你的背影
I see you on your back.
周围血迹斑斑
There's blood everywhere.
你手里捧着你的心脏
You're holding your own heart in your hand.
它停止了跳动
It's not beating.
我没有时间听你的鬼话
I don't have time for this shit.
我五岁的时候
When I was five,
就预见到父母的死
I knew how my own parents would die.
然后，我就在后座目睹死亡的发生
Then I watched it happen from the back seat.
看着我
Look at me.
许多人都要我的命
A lot of people have tried to kill me,
但是我还在这
and I'm still here.
但是你如今不同了
But you're different now, aren't you?
他们能伤害你
They can hurt you.
他们能杀死你
They can kill you.
你乖乖留在车上
Just wait in the car.
- 我说，留在车上  - 你需要支援
- I said, wait in the car. - You need backup.
你目前的状态，你并不安全
You're not safe, not in your condition.
就当我是你的随身保镖
Just think of me as your bodyguard.
性感啊
Sexy.
来吧！我要上了
Come on! I'm coming.
等我一下哟
第四轮 我们一饮而尽
Okay, round four. Here we go.
屁股不错嘛
女士们，干杯
Drink for you, my lady.
出去
Get out.
不是说你
Not you.
说我过时也好…
Call me old-fashioned...
但是我认为订婚以后
But I thought being engaged meant
你就别乱搞
you were done with this kind of bullshit.
我是法务大臣
I am the minister of justice.
你知道我能怎样整死你吗？
Do you have any idea what I could do to you?
真的？你以为穿个红色内裤
Really? You're gonna try and talk tough,
就能装成硬汉要挟我吗？
standing there in your red underwear?
我让你再说十个字…
You have ten words...
只有十个字…
Ten words...
跟我解释一下，为什么你一个法务大臣…
To explain to me why you, the minister of justice...
要让你的未婚妻死于矢志田一族刀下？
Would want your fiance killed by the Yakuza.
如果我不满意你的答案
And if I don't like what you say,
我就把你扔出这个窗外
you are going through that fucking window.
你压根就不知道将要…
You don't have the faintest idea what's going on...
- 他说了多少个字了？  - 九个
- How many words was that? - Nine.
九个 你还有一个字剩下
Nine. You have one word left.
玩真的？
Really?
信玄 信玄！
继续说
Keep going.
自从他病了后…
Since he got sick...
矢志田老头子花费数亿元看病、治疗
Old man Yashida spent billions on doctors, healers.
在他北方的研究所大量贮备艾德曼合金…
Stockpiling adamantium at his lab in the north...
秘密研究延长寿命的方法
Secretly trying to prolong his life.
他把公司推向破产的边缘
He brought the company to the edge of bankruptcy.
他对你入了迷
He was obsessed with you.
东武的干部们全都…
说人话！
English!
信玄撒谎了，为了保护这个老头…
Shingen lied, protected the old man...
对股东和董事会隐瞒了巨债
Concealed the debt from stockholders and the board.
他要成为个好孩子，以为自己会得到奖赏
He tried to be a good son and thought he'd be rewarded.
结果老头把所有都留给了孙女
And then the old man left everything to his granddaughter.
如果真理子掌控大权，她会甩掉他
If Mariko got all that power, she would dump his ass.
说得没错
It's true.
真理子绝对不会完成这场婚姻…
Mariko would have never gone through with the wedding...
只要遗嘱公诸于世
Not once the will was revealed.
她从来都不管我
She never took to me.
真的吗？你真是正人君子
Oh, really? A class act like you.
信玄答应事成给我一笔钱
Shingen promised me a fortune for my help.
所以你要追杀他的女儿 是这样吗？
So, you put a hit on his daughter. Is that it?
官场沉浮谁能主宰
Political careers don't last forever.
没错
That's right.
等下！等下！不！
Wait! Wait! No!
你要真相 我给了你真相！
You wanted the truth. I told you the truth!
我不喜欢
I didn't like it.
你怎么知道下面有个泳池？
How did you know there's a pool down there?
我不知道的
I didn't.
你知道我在大学修读的是生物学？
遗传学
有许多基因跳过了遗传
隐性基因
眼睛
眼睛 毛发
才能
性格
每个孩子获得了不同的基因
我的父亲在我身上看不到自己的影子
但在你的身上…
他好像看着块镜子一样
你是如何说服我的父亲…
让你来掌控…
全亚洲最大型的企业？
你疯了
我只是在觉醒
如果你杀了我，你会失去…
仅存不多的荣誉
真理子，别害怕
我不是要伤害你
我想要帮助你
帮你解除你的痛苦…
让你重做上周…
那个变种人阻止你做的事
我从没想过要死，父亲
放开我
没事了，真理子
跟我走
发生什么事？！
超出你所想象的
是你
You.
是我
Me.
打扰你们不好意思，不过我要你女儿的活着
Sorry to interrupt, but I need your daughter alive.
你究竟是谁？
What are you?
化学家，虚无主义者…
A chemist, a nihilist...
资本家，变种人
A capitalist, a mutation.
我是毒蛇
A viper.
守卫都上哪去了？
Where is the security?
矢志田的人
Yakuza.
信玄？
Shingen?
罗根？
Logan.
（来找她）
这里 看这
This. This here.
这是哪里？
Where is this?
矢志田主人出生的地方
Master Yashida's birthplace.
公司在山中的一个建筑
The company built a facility into the mountainside.
有多远？
How far?
离这里500公里
500 kilometers from here.
我要把这个东西弄出体外
I gotta get that thing out of me.
怎么做？
How?
不，停下，罗根
No, stop, Logan.
我预见你的死亡 我不会错的
I saw you die. I'm never wrong.
- 我从没错过  - 你不是一直都对的
- I'm never wrong. - You're not always right.
你预见不到老头要咬它
You didn't know the old man was gonna bite it.
我看到你在这样的房间
I saw you die in a room like this
手里捧着你的心脏
with your heart in your hand.
我不能让她和那些怪物杀手在一起
I can't leave her with those freaks and killers.
我是她唯一的机会
I'm the only chance she's got,
但是先要弄走那个东西
but not with that thing inside me.
你会死的，罗根
You're going to die, Logan.
或许我没事
Maybe that's okay.
不，听我说，罗根！
No, listen to me, Logan!
不要，停下 罗根！
No, stop. Logan!
你不会喜欢接下来这一幕
You're not gonna want to watch this part.
不！听我说！求你，不要！
No! Listen to me! Please, no!
不，停手 听我说
No, stop. Listen to me.
罗根！
Logan!
让开！
Move!
不要碰他！
Stay away from him.
是他杀了你的主人
He killed your master.
又勾搭上了你的姐姐
Put hands on your sister.
现在你却护着他？
And now you want him?
不 我看不见了
Oh, no. I can't see.
你永远只能是个乞丐
You'll always be a beggar.
你疯了
You're crazy.
惨了
Oh, no.
雪绪
Yukio.
罗根！
Logan!
罗根！罗根！
Logan! Logan!
罗根！
Logan!
不要打我的朋友
Don't hit my friends.
真理子在哪里？
Where's Mariko?
她被带走了 毒蛇抢走了她
She's gone. That viper bitch took her.
就是因为我的父亲的执念…
It was my father's obsession...
对变种沉迷，对上帝的错误沉迷…
With mutation, with God's mistakes...
像你和她一样
Like you and her,
毁了这个家族
that ruined this house.
你要杀死自己的亲生女儿
You tried to kill your daughter.
背负这个恶名吧
Live with that.
你究竟是何方妖怪？
What kind of monster are you?
我是金刚狼
The Wolverine.
看着我，看着我 对了
Hey, come here, come here. That's it.
我错了
I was wrong.
我就说过
I told you.
让我瞧瞧
Let me have a look at you.
什么事也没有
It's nothing.
谢谢你
Hey, thank you.
（来找她）
那是陷阱，罗根
It's a trap, Logan.
你为什么带我来这里？
你在隐藏什么东西？
你很快就会知道了
欢迎，真理子
Welcome, Mariko.
真理子，别害怕
It's all right, Mariko.
她也是矢志田一家的
She also serves the house of Yashida.
她只效忠于自己
She serves herself.
她感染了罗根
She infected Logan.
那么爷爷呢？
And what about grandfather?
你让他感染什么？
What did you infect him with?
我满足了他临死时的愿望
I granted his dying wish.
我让他安眠
I helped him rest.
现在轮到你了
Now, it's your turn.
过来帮忙
听我说，变种人
Listen to me, mutant.
她不能受到伤害
She will not be harmed.
她不会有事的
She will be fine.
只要你完成你的职责
So long as you do your job.
罗根很快就赶到了，你该准备好
Logan will be here soon, you should prepare.
引他过来是很容易
It was easy to lure him here.
要捉住他又是另外一回事了
It's another thing to capture him.
我们准备好 他从没和黑色联盟交过手
We're ready. He's never faced the black clan.
好的，那么…
Yes, well...
往你的箭头上蘸点这个
Dip your arrows in this.
杀不死他
It won't kill him,
但是能把他困住
but it will slow him down.
收好你的毒药
Keep your potions.
他对付不了我们的 他很弱
He's no challenge for us now. He's weak.
好吧
okay.
如果你们失败了…
but when you fail...
你们还有这个
You have this.
你睡得香吗？
Did you have a nice rest?
我不知道你做了什么
I don't know what you said or did
可以欺骗原田和我的爷爷…
to deceive Harada or my grandfather...
冷静一下
Now, now, calm down.
是你的爷爷寻求我的帮助
Your grandfather sought me out.
我现在是家族的主人
I am the head of this family now.
你为什么会这么认为呢？
And why do you suppose that is?
你为什么以为老头选中了你？
Why do you think the old man chose you?
因为你强大？
Because you are strong?
还是因为你软弱？
Or because you are weak?
我知道你要来打架
I see you've come to fight.
但这毫无意义
It's pointless.
你很弱 寡不敌众的
You're weak. You're outnumbered.
黑色联盟守护矢志田家族
The black clan has protected the house of Yashida
已经有700年历史
for 700 years.
你就带了这么点人马？
Is that all the men you brought?
我要去救她
I'm gonna get her.
我们会感激你奋力保护真理子
We are grateful for your protection of Mariko.
但是你要为她的家族再牺牲一件事
But there is one more sacrifice you must make for her family.
滚一边去，小白脸
Go fuck yourself, pretty boy.
开干！
破风！上！
雪绪，快跑！
Yukio, run!
罗根
Logan.
凯拉
Kayla.
我爱你 凯拉！
I love you. Kayla!
罗根
Logan.
罗根！真理子！
Logan! Mariko!
珍
Jean.
救救我
Save me.
退后 没有必要
Stand back. There is no need.
她在哪里？真理子在哪里？
Where is she? Where's Mariko?
她在哪里？
Where is she?
“真理子在哪里？”
"Where is Mariko?"
为伊消得人憔悴？
Still pining away?
真是甜蜜
That's so sweet.
惊讶吗？
Impressive, no?
他是由艾德曼合金制成，和你一样
He is made of adamantium, just like you.
罗根，知道吗，我懂了
Oh, Logan, you know what, I get it.
你绝望了
You're frustrated.
我知道她在这里 我要见她
I know she's here. I want to see her.
你要答案
You want answers.
没错，我要答案！
Yes, I want answers!
对不起，我也想说的更多
I'm sorry, I wish I could say more,
但是谨慎才让我谋到这份工作
but I was hired in part for my discretion.
我肯定你是
I'm sure you were.
谨慎…
That...
还有某种天分
and a certain talent
结合了生物化学和玄学方面的
for combining biochemistry and metaphysics.
高等毒药是我的专长
High-grade toxins are my specialty.
帮助我从遗传上免疫
It helps to be genetically immune
人类所知的每样毒物，如我所是
to every poison known to man, as I am.
也让我对男性的吸引力免疫…
And immune to the toxin that is man himself...
如我所是
As I am.
我跟你说，你这个变态变种贱人…
I'll tell you what, you twisted mutant bitch...
何不解开我的手铐
Why don't you open these bracelets
然后看看我们谁更厉害呢？
and we'll see who's made of what?
爪子来了 我们可以开始
The claws. Now we can begin.
我知道你关心他
你需要忘了他
你是矢志田家族的
她背叛了我的爷爷
你也一样
不，真理子
我们一起长大
你要相信我
让我去救他！
他救了我的命！
忘了他，真理子！
这对我来说不容易，但是…
我是追随爷爷的意愿
你在你的体内找到的抑制虫是我的杰作
The suppressant bug you found inside of you was mine.
你竟然自己取了出来
You took it out on your own.
这点是我无法预料的
I didn't see that coming.
毒蛇女人是邪恶的…
你我都知道
但她是完结一切的工具…
她在哪里？
Where is she?
你的爷爷想要的终结
你很坚强
You are strong.
也有勇气
You have courage.
真正的勇气
Real courage.
但是没有多大用处
But that won't help much now.
什么…？
What the...?
你需要相信我
有那么难吗？
我们命中注定在一起
我们仍然还是
或许吧
住手！
Stop!
简直是疯了
我们走
Let's go.
走啊！
Go!
快跑！
Run!
快走
Come on.
真理子，快跑！跑啊！
Mariko, come! Go! Run!
真理子，出去！
Mariko, get out!
快点
Come on.
这不是解决的方法
This is not the way.
双手握紧
Two hands.
主人…
Master...
老弟！
Bub!
原田
对不起
现在，你要死了
Now, you die.
今天不是我的死期
Today is not my day.
罗根君
Logan-San.
不要这么惊讶
Don't look so shocked.
有了你的帮助，我在长崎活下来了
With you at my side, I survived Nagasaki.
自然，这次我也不会死
Surely, I could survive this.
没关系 会让你死得痛快
It's all right. It won't take long.
格林医生和我一直在等待机会
Dr. green and I have been waiting.
只有这件装甲能让我存活下去
It's only this armor that's kept me alive.
打造它让我变得强大
We built it to make me strong,
让我拿走你不愿意给的
so I can take what you would not give.
把你不想要的复原能力…
And transfer your unwanted healing...
传送给我的身体
To my body.
我的遗产必须保存下去
My legacy must be preserved.
你的错误是以为没有终结的生命…
Your mistake was to believe that a life without end...
没有意义
Can have no meaning.
这才是生命的意义
It is the only life that can.
等一下
Hold on.
我们快要完成了
We are almost there.
宁静，你一直想要的宁静
The peace, the peace you've wanted.
你的奖赏
Your reward.
我在给予你彻底的死亡…
You know, I'm giving you the very death...
你渴望的死亡
You longed for.
我感觉到…
This feeling...
无敌的感觉…
To be invincible...
就和你一样
Like you.
你是个怪物
真理子
Mariko.
是我 你的爷爷啊
It's me. Your grandfather.
我亲手埋葬了我的爷爷
I buried my grandfather.
你叫我来道别
You asked me to come say goodbye.
永别了
Sayonara.
没事吧你？
Are you all right?
罗根
Logan.
你来了
You're here.
没错
Of course.
能留下吗？
Can you stay?
我不能
I can't.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
这是你所追求的
This is what you wanted.
不再是了
Not anymore.
我在这很寂寞
I'm all alone here.
你把我送到这里
You put me here.
你伤害了人，珍
You were hurting people, Jean.
我别无选择
I had to.
我爱你，珍
I love you, Jean.
永生不变
I always will.
我不会寂寞的
虽然只有你一个亲人了
姐姐，多珍重
我怎么觉得你很快会再探访我呢？
Am I wrong to think you might visit me soon?
留下吧
Stay.
我不能，公主阁下
I can't, princess.
我是名战士
I'm a soldier,
我已经躲藏了太久
and I've been hiding too long.
今晚《商业剖析》的头条，是矢志田真理子
In our business profile tonight, Mariko Yashida.
矢志田两代之间传承家族的火炬…
A two-generation passing of the torch in the Yashida family...
矢志田真理子从其爷爷手中接掌大权
As Mariko Yashida takes the helm from her grandfather,
曾建立科技巨头的那个人
who built this tech giant.
我知道一个企业的目的
I know it will always be the purpose
是创造利益…
for a corporation to make a profit...
但是矢志田工业坚信
But Yashida industries believes
可以和社会携手合作
we can also work with our community.
那么，你决定了吗？
So, have you decided?
什么？
What?
真理子说我们想去哪里都可以
Mariko says we can go wherever we want.
只要说一个目的地
Just say where.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我是你的随身保镖
I'm your bodyguard.
那么，你的目的地是哪里？
So, where do you want to go?
咱们先起飞吧
Let's just start with up.
然后呢？
And then?
再说吧
We'll see.
真有趣
Interesting.
（温馨提示：后面有彩蛋）
金刚狼
（两年后）
依靠尖端的科技
With cutting edge technology,
和引领世界的意识…
and the world's leading minds...
我们走在时代的前沿…
We are on the front lines...
保护您的健康，保护您的安全
Keeping you healthy, keeping you safe.
查斯克工业
（制造“哨兵”机器人的公司）
Trask industries.
以今天的科技，解决明天的问题
Solving tomorrow's problems, today.
等我卸下假肢
I'll take the pat-down.
解除警报
Opt out.
你可以通过了，先生
You can go ahead, sir.
我还是等一下
I'll wait.
你要什么？
What do you want?
出现了一股黑暗势力，金刚狼
There are dark forces, Wolverine.
人类军队在建造一个武器…
Human forces building a weapon...
可以让我们变种人灭亡
That could bring about the end of our kind.
我想要什么？我要你的帮忙
What do I want? I want your help.
我凭什么相信你？
Why would I trust you?
你不必信我
You wouldn't.
你好，罗根
Hello, Logan.
这怎么可能？
How is this possible?
很久以前我就和你说过…
As I told you a long time ago...
拥有天赋的不止你一个
You are not the only one with gifts.